American Philosophical Society Archives. Record Group IIf. 1866-1886 APS.Archives.IIf APS.Archives.IIf
American Philosophical Society
- Papers
  - Letter to Jos[eph] Carson, March 28, 1876; 9x6; A. J. Holman Company (Philadelphia, Pa.)
    Phila., L. 1p. Enc. Encloses copy of John Welsh's letter of recommendation for loan of Eliot Bible for display at the Centennial.
  - Letter to Eli K[irk] Price, March 28, 1876; 9x6; A. J. Holman Company (Philadelphia, Pa.)
    Phila., L. 1p. Enc. wanting Encloses letter from John Welsh recommending loan of Eliot Bible for display at Centennial. For enclosure, see Welsh to A.P.S., March 25, 1876.
  - Letter to [Benjamin Hornor] Coates, March 31, 1876; 8x5; Price, Eli K. (Eli Kirk), 1797-1884
    [Phila.] A.L.S. 1p. Concerns loan of Eliot Bible to A.J. Holman & Co. for Centennial display. Refers to G.H. Horn.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, March, 1876; 11 x8-1/2; Hollandsche Maatschappij der Wetenschappen
    Haarlem, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: E.H.von Baumhauer. 1p.,end. In French. Forwards publications.
  - Letter to Prof. [J.P.] Lesley, April 8, 1876; 8-1/2x5-1/2; A. J. Holman Company (Philadelphia, Pa.)
    Phila., L. 1p., end. Concerning loan of John Eliot Bible from Society for Centennial exhibition.
  - Letter to J.P. Lesley, April 22, 1876; 8x5; Phillips, Henry M. (Henry Myer), 1811-1884
    A.L.S. 1p., end. Declines to write obituary of Theodore Cuyler.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, April, 1876; 10-1/2x9D; Gesellschaft zur Beförderung der Gesammten Naturwissenschaften zu Marburg
    Marburg, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: O.v.Heusinger 1p.,end. In German. Forwards publications.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, May 4, 1876; 10x8; Geological Survey of Pennsylvania
    Harrisburg, L.S.: Jno. B. Pearse. 1p.,end. Forwards publications.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, [May?], 1876; 11x8-1/2; Die schweizerische gesellschaft in Bern.
    Bern Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: T.R.Koche. 1p.,end. In German. Forwards publications.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, June 1, 1876; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Königlich Sächsische Gesellschaft der Wissenschaften zu Leipzig
    Leipzig, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: H.L.Fleischer 2p.,end. In German. Forwards publications.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, June 1, 1876; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Königlich Sächsische Gesellschaft der Wissenschaften zu Leipzig
    Leipzig, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: W. Hankel. 2p.,end. In German. Forwards publications.
  - Letter to secretary of A.P.S. [J.P. Lesley], June 17, 1876; 10x8; Nicholson, W. L.
    Washington, A.L.S. 1p., end.by M[ary] L[esley]. Writing for J.Henry. Needs date of Joseph Saxton's election to Society.
  - Letter to J.P. Lesley, June 21, 1876; 8x5; Kesselmeyer, Charles Augustus
    Manchester, Eng., A.L.S. 2p., end.and enc. Offers Calendarium perpetuum mobile as gift. Enclosure is picture of calendar with an explanation.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the American philosophical society, July 6, 1876; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Engelmann, George, 1809-1884
    St. Louis, A.L.S. 1p.,end. Forwards publications.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, July 12, 1876; 10-1/2x8; Royal Society of New South Wales
    Sydney, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Archd. Liversedge. 1p.,end. Forwards publication.
  - Letter to secretary of A.P.S.[J.P.Lesley], July 20, 1876; 8x5; Smithsonian Institution
    Washington, L.S.: Joseph Henry, by R. 1p., end. Announces death of J.J.Kaup.
  - Letter to [Pliny Earle] Chase, July 22, 1876; 8x5; Matile, G.-A. (George-Auguste), 1807-1881
    Washington, A.L.S. 2p., end. Concerns loan of pieces from Poinsett collection for his use. Refers to A.H. Guyot. Cf. Proceedings, v.16, pp.287-8.
  - Letter to Pliny E. Chase, July 26, 1876; 8x5; Anthon, Charles Edward, 1822-1883
    New York, A.L.S. 1p. Changing of name and title on ms.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, July, 1876; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Kungl. Svenska vetenskapsakademien
    Stockholm, Printed L.filled in in ms. 1p.,end. In French. Forwards publications.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Aug. 15, Dec. 2, 1876; 10-1/2x8-1/2; St. Petersburg. Jardin impériale de botanique
    St. Petersburg, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: E.Negely(?). 1p.,end. In French. Forwards publications.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Aug. 17, 1876; 10x8; United States. Dept. of State
    Washington, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Hamilton Fish 1p.,end. Forwards publications.
  - Letter to Dr. J.P. Lesli [sic], Aug. 18, 1876; 8x5; United States. Weather Bureau
    Washington, A.L.S.: Cleveland Abbe. 1p., end. Asks to borrow periodical from Society on meteorology.
  - Letter to Prof. Pliny E. Chase, Aug. 21, 1876; 10x7-1/2; Cresson, Charles M. (Charles Massey), 1828-1893
    Phila., L.S. 1p., end. Sends receipt (wanting). Discusses goods to be sent. Mentions O.Marsh.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society and the Academy of Natural Sciences, Aug. 21, 1876; 8x5; Guyot, A. (Arnold), 1807-1884
    [Big Indian] [N.Y., 1876] A.L.S 2p., end.: Recd. Aug. 21, 1876 Recommends G.A Matile to work on Poinsett collection.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Aug., 1876; 8x5; U.S. Coast and Geodetic Survey
    Washington, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: J.E.Hilgard. 1p.and add.,end. Forwards publication.
  - Note to J.P. Lesley, Sept. 8, 1876; 11-1/2x9; Kesselmeyer, Charles Augustus
    Manchester, Eng., A.N.in 3rd P.with picture of Calendarium perpetuum mobile. 1p.and end. Offers Calendarium perpetuum mobile as gift.
  - Note to American philosophical society, Sept. 9, 1876; 3-1/2x2; Kesselmeyer, Charles Augustus
    Manchester, Eng., A.N.on calling card S. 1p.and add. Sending explanation of Calendarium perpetuum mobile.
  - Letter to American philosophical society, Sept. 23, 1876; 8x5; Wood, H. C. (Horatio C.), 1841-1920
    A.L.S. 1p. Won't part with memoir on myriapoda; suggests Society make it available.
  - Letter to Jno. McArthur, Sept. 26, 1876; 8" x 10"; Blodget, Lorin, 1823-1901
    A.L.S. 2p. and end. Corrects a misunderstanding which appeared in APS Proceedings relative to insecurity of public building of the city due to the sand gravels of the general city foundation.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Sept. 29, 1876; 11x8-1/2; Kaiserl. Akademie der Wissenschaften in Wien
    Vienna, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: H.Siegel. 2p.,end. In German. Forwards publications.
  - Letter to Pliny E[arle] Chase, Oct. 6, 1876; 8x5; Guyot, A. (Arnold), 1807-1884
    Princeton, N.J., A.L.S. 2p. and end. G.A. Matile will return pieces from Poinsett collection, together with copies of same pieces in the Princeton collection.
  - Letter to [the American philosophical society; read], Oct. 20, 1876; 10-1/2x8-1/2; Académie royale des sciences, des lettres et des beaux-arts de Belgique
    Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: J.Liagre. 1p.,end. In French. Forwards publications.
  - Report on proposed exchange of duplicates in the Poinsett collection with duplicates in the Princeton archaeological collection, Nov. 3, 1876; 10x8; American Philosophical Society. Curators
    Phila., D.S.: J[oseph] Carson, Charles M. Cresson 1p., end.: Wrote to Prof. Guyot, Nov. 4, 1876, J. P[eter] L[esley] (see A.P.S. Curators. Reports) Refers to G.A. Matile. Cf. Proceedings, v.16, p.290.
  - Letter to secretary of A.P.S.[J.P.Lesley], Nov. 3, 1876; 8x5; Hayward, W. S.
    Onondaga Valley, N.Y., A.L.S. 2p., end.by M[ary] L[esley]. Looking for D.Zeisberger's works on the language of the Onondaga Indians.
  - Letter to Prof. J.P. Lesley, Nov. 8, 1876; 8x5; Guyot, A. (Arnold), 1807-1884
    Princeton, A.L.S. 2p., end. Exchange of duplicates in Poinsett and Princeton collections, arranged through Prof.Matile.
  - Letter to Prof. J.P. Lesley, Nov. 13, 1876; 8x5; Baird, Spencer Fullerton, 1823-1887
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Thanks for favor.
  - Letter to J.P. Lesley, Nov. 21, 1876; 10x8; Fraley, F. (Frederick), 1804-1901
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p., end. Names Rogers, Barker, Britton, Briggs, Ingham to committee to consider J.Wootten for 500 dollar premium for the best invention for utilizing anthracite coal-dust. Award to be paid out of income of Magellanic fund.
  - Letter to J.P. Lesley, Nov. 25, 1876; 10x8; Literary and Philosophical Society of Liverpool
    Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Alfred Morgan. 1p., end. Forwards publication.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Dec. 1, 1876; 13x8; Bataviaasche genootschap von kunsten en wetenschappen
  - Letter to Prof. J.P. Lesley, Dec. 2, 1876; 9x5-1/2; Linn, John Blair, 1831-1899
    Bellefonte, Pa., A.L.S. 1p., end. Asks to borrow J.Burd journals.
  - Letter to president of American philosophical society, Dec. 9, 1876; 10x8-1/2; Smith, Charles E.
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p., end. Resigns membership in Society.
  - Letter to J.P[eter] Lesley, Dec. 13, 1876; 8-1/2x5; Guyot, A. (Arnold), 1807-1884
    Princeton, N.J., A.L.S. 2p. Arranged to returned borrowed pieces from Poinsett collection. Refers to G.A. Matile.
  - Letter to American philosophical society, Dec. 20, 1876; 10x8; Pennsylvania. Secretary of the Commonwealth
    Harrisburg, A.L.S.: John B[lair] Linn. 1p., end. Saw J.Burd journals with Dr.Egle; no funds for copying them. Will send publications, if needed.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Dec., 1876; 11x9; Königlich Bayerische Akademie der Wissenschaften
    Munich, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: J. Aumer. 1p.,end. In German. Forwards publications.
  - Letter to Pliny E[arle] chase, 1876; 8x5; Guyot, A. (Arnold), 1807-1884
    Big Indian, N.Y., A.L.S. 1p Enc. Sends letter of recommendation for G.A. Matile. Concerns Poinsett collection. For enclosure, see Guyor to A.P.S. AND Academy of Natural Sciences [1876] /cf. Proceedings, v.16, pp.287-288.
  - Report on loan of Eliot Indian Bible., [1876]; American Philosophical Society. Library committee
    A.D.S. 1p.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society and Academy of [Natural] Science, [1876]; Guyot, A. (Arnold), 1807-1884
  - Letter to Prof.[J.P.] Lesley, Jan. 5, 1877; 8x5; Kane, Thomas Leiper, 1822-1883
    A.L.S. 1p. Requests change in title of manuscript.
  - Letter to J.P. Lesley, Jan. 11, 1877; 10x8; Pennsylvania. Secretary of the Commonwealth
    Harrisburg, A.L.S.: John B[lair] Linn. 1p.,end. Gratitude for loan of two Col.Burd journals from Society.
  - Letter to J.P. Lesley, Jan. 15, 1877; 8x5; Rogers, R. E. (Robert Empie), 1813-1884
    A.L.S. 1p., end. Committee to meet to consider J.Wootten application.
  - Letter to J.P. Lesley, Jan. 24, 1877; 8x5; Biddle, John B. (John Barclay), 1815-1879
    A.L.S. 1p., end. Accepts appointment to write obituary of Joseph Carson.
  - Letter to J. P[eter] Lesley, Philadelphia, Jan. 26, 1877; 10x8; Linn, John Blair, 1831-1899
    Harrisburg, A.L.S. 1p.,end. Returns Byrd's journal with thanks for the loan.
  - Letter to Prof. J.P. Lesley, Jan. 29, 1877; 8x5; LeConte, John, 1818-1891
    Berkeley, A.L.S. 2p., end. Wishes Trans.for University of California; also, Francis Hopkinson's works.
  - Letter to the Librarian of the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Jan. 31, 1877; 8x5; United States Naval Observatory.
    Washington, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: C.H.Davis. 1p.,end.and end. Forwards publication.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Feb. 2, 1877; 11x8-1/2; Societas Regia Scientiarum Upsaliensis
    Upsal, [read] Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: O.Glas. 1p.,end. In French. Forwards publications.
  - Letter to Prof.[J.P.] Lesley, Feb. 23, 1877; 8x5; Cope, E. D. (Edward Drinker), 1840-1897
    A.L.S. 1p. Sends manuscript on Dinosauria. Will exhibit Saurian bones at next meeting of A.P.S.
  - Letter to Prof.[J.P.] Lesley, March 5, 1877; 8x5; Cope, E. D. (Edward Drinker), 1840-1897
    A.L.S. 2p., end. Concerning manuscripts on paleontology.
  - Letter to American philosophical society, March 13, 1877; 8x5; Porter, Thomas C. (Thomas Conrad), 1822-1901
    Easton, Pa., A.L.S. 1p., end. About E.A.Barber and his work on Indian antiquities. Refers to David Townsend and William Darlington.
  - Letter to American philosophical society, March 23, 1877; 8x5; Cope, E. D. (Edward Drinker), 1840-1897
    A.L.S. 1p., end. Is sending manuscript on coryphodon. Society should furnish plates for it.
  - Letter to the Librarian [of the American philosophical society], March, 1877; 10-1/2x9; Royal Observatory, Greenwich
    London, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: A.W.Downing. 1p., end. Forwarded publications.
  - Letter to the Librarian of the American philosophical society, April 3, 1877; Harvard University Observatory
  - Letter to secretary of American philosophical society [J.P.Lesley], May 2, [1877]; 8x5; Kerr, Washington Caruthers, 1827-1885
    N.Y., A.L.S. 2p., end.by M[ary] L[esley]. Needs loan of wood-cut.
  - Letter to Prof. [J.P.] Lesley, May 5, 1877; 8x5-1/2; Cope, E. D. (Edward Drinker), 1840-1897
    A.L.S. 1p.and enc. Concerning plate for his paper on paleontology. Enclosure is pencil sketch of plate. On same sheet is letter from Mary Lesley to LeConte, [1877].
  - Letter to Mary Lesley, June 1, 1877; 10x8; Kerr, Washington Caruthers, 1827-1885
    Raleigh, N.C., A.L.S. 2p., end. Wants to know whether wood-cut has been located.
  - Letter to the President of the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, June 1, 1877; 10-1/2x8-1/2; Société de géographie commerciale de Bordeaux
    Bordeaux, L.S.: P.Foncin. 1p.,end. In French. Forwards publications.
  - Letter to the Librarian of the American Philosophical Society, June 5, 1877; Harvard University Observatory
  - Letter to Mary Lesley, June 11, 1877; 10x8; Kerr, Washington Caruthers, 1827-1885
    Raleigh, N.C., A.L.S. 1p. Grateful for favor in trying to locate wood-cut.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, June, 1877; 9x6; Kungl. Svenska vetenskapsakademien
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, July 1, 1877; 11x9; Königlich Bayerische Akademie der Wissenschaften
    Munich, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: J.Aumer. 1p.,end. In German. Forwards publications.
  - Letter to Prof. [J.P.] Lesley, July 6, 1877; 8x5; Draper, Henry, 1837-1882
    Dobbs Ferry, N.Y., A.L.S. 3p., end. Concerning his paper on astronomical photography. Mentions father(J.W. Draper).
  - Letter to the Secretary of the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, July 11, 1877; 10-1/2x8; Royal Society of New South Wales
    Sydney, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Archd. Liversedge. 2p.,end. Forwards publications.
  - Letter to American philosophical society, July 13, 1877; 10x8; Matile, G.-A. (George-Auguste), 1807-1881
    Washington, A.L.S. 1p., end. Received letter from Prof,Guyot about loan of specimens to Princeton.
  - Letter to [the American philosophical society], Aug., 1877; 6x1/2x8-1/2; Museo Nacional de México
    Mexico, Printed L.S.; Gumesindo Mendoza. 1p. Forwards publication.
  - Letter to Prof. J.P. Lesley, Sept. 28, 1877; 11x8-1/2; White, I. C. (Israel Charles), 1848-1927
    Morgantown, W.Va., A.L.S. 2p., end. Refers to expense account. Discusses proof plates of fossil plants and work with Prof.Fontaine; also, mentions Prof. Lesquereux. Asks for Society's aid in publishing.
  - Letter to [Hector] Tyndale [and] Curators, Oct. 2, 1877; 10-1/2x8; Patterson, Robert, 1819?-1909
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. and end. Recommends transfer of Peale Stone Age collection to Academy of Natural Sciences which is fireproof, a condition of C.E.G. Peale's bequest. Cf. Proceedings, v.17, pp.13-15.
  - Report on the Peale Stone Age collection given to the A.P.S. by C.E.G. Peale, Oct. 5, 1877; 12-1/2x8; American Philosophical Society. Curators
    [Phila.] D. 1p., end., and end. (see A.P.S. Curators. Reports) Cf. Proceedings, v.17, pp.13-15. Recommends collection be transferred to the Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia. Not found May, 2011.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Oct. 19, 1877; 8x5; Cambridge Philosophical Society
    Cambridge, [read] Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: J.W.L.Glaisher 1p. Forwards publications.
  - Letter to Hector Tyndale and Charles M. Cresson, Curators, Oct. 25, 1877; 10x8; Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia
    Phila., A.L.S.: W[illiam] S[amuel] W[aithman] Ruschenberger 1p., end. Accepts deposit of Peale Stone Age collection. Cf. Proceedings, v.17, pp.272-273.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Philadelphia, Oct., 1877; 8x5; Great Britain. Meteorological Office
    London, Printed L.S.: Robert H. Scott. 1p. and add.,end. Forwards publication.
  - Letter to the A.P.S. Curators, Nov. 7, 1877; 10-1/2x8-1/2; Patterson, Robert, 1819?-1909
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p., end.: Ref. to Secy to be read... Nov.16, 1877. Requests power to arrange for deposit of Peale Stone Age collection at Academy of Natural Sciences.
  - Receipt for Franklin Peale Stone Age collection, deposited by A.P.S., Nov. 13, 1877; 10-1/2x8-1/2; Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia
    Phila., Printed form filled in in Ms., S.: George H[enry] Horn 1p., end., and end. Cf. Proceedings, v.17, pp.272-3.
  - Letter to [the American philosophical society], Nov. 18, 1877; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Halle. Geographische Gesellschaft
    Halle, A.L.S.: Lehmann. 1p.,end. Forwards Publication.
  - Letter to American philosophical society, Nov. 21, 1877; 7x4-1/2; Royal Institution of Great Britain
    London, A.L.S.:Benj[amin] Vincent, librarian. 3p. and end. Received publications. Gives list of Trans. and asks that deficiencies be supplied. Refers to Count Rumford.
  - Letter to [the American philosophical society], Nov., 1877; 8x5; U.S. Coast and Geodetic Survey
    Washington, Printed L.S.: J.E.Hilgard. 1p.,end. Forwards publication.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, [Dec. 12, 1887]; Snyder, Monroe Benjamin, 1848-
  - Letter to J.P. Lesley, Jan. 14, 1878; 10x8; Grace, R. W.
    Bedalia, Mo., A.L.S. 1p.,end...Enc.wanting.... Concerning invention for locomotives.
  - Letter to Prof. J.P. Lesley, April 12, 1878; 7x4; Rogers, R. E. (Robert Empie), 1813-1884
    A.L.S. 1p.and end. Meeting of committee on J.Wootten application.
  - Letter to J. Sergeant Price, treasurer of the American philosophical society, May 3, 1878; 10-1/2x8; Miller, J. Imbrie
    L.S. 1p.and end. Resigns membership in Society.
  - Letter to Prof. J.P. Lesley, May 15, 1878; 5x3; Gurley, Wm. F. E. (William Frank Eugene Reed), b. 1854
    Danville, Ill., A.L.on postal card S. 1p., end.and add. Concerning disposition of his paper on paleontology, referred to Society by E.D.Cope
  - Letter to J. Sergeant Price, June 13, 1878; 10-1/2x8; Miller, J. Imbrie
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p., end. Pays dues subsequent to resigning membership in Society.
  - Letter to J.P. Lesley, June 14, 1878; 7-1/2x4-1/2; Price, John Sergeant, 1831-1897
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p.and end. Resignation from Society of J.Imbrie Miller.
  - Letter to [J.P.] Lesley, June 15, 1878; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Haldeman, Samuel Steman, 1812-1880
    Chicki[e]s, Pa., A.L.S. 2p.,end. Finishing paper on Indian antiquities. Lists some specimens. Refers to J.Leidy.
  - Letter to Prof. J.P. Lesley, June 17, 1878; 5x3; Monks, Sarah P.
    Coldspring, N.Y., A.L.on postal card S. 1p., end.and add. Wishes copies of her paper on turtles. Mentions E.D.Cope.
  - Letter to J.P. Lesley, June 19, 1878; 5x3; Gurley, Wm. F. E. (William Frank Eugene Reed), b. 1854
    Danville, Ill., A.L.on postal card S. 1p., end.and add. Concerning proof of paper on paleontology.
  - Letter to Prof. J.P. Lesley, June 20, 1878; 5x3; Monks, Sarah P.
    Coldspring, N.Y., A.L.on postal card S. 1p., end.and add. Concerning plates for her paper on turtles. Refers to J.E.Gray.
  - Letter to the secretaries of the American philosophical society, July 1, 1878; 10x8; Lautenbach, B. F.
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Offers paper on physiology. Refers to S.Weir Mitchell.
  - Letter to Prof. J.P. Lesley, July 1, 1878; 8x5; Rogers, Fairman, 1833-1900
    Newport, R.I., A.L.S. 2p., end. Agrees to write obituary of J.Henry.
  - Letter to Prof. J.P. Lesley, July 5, 1878; 10-1/2x8; Ashburner, Charles A. (Charles Albert), 1854-1889
    Kane, [Pa.], A.L.S. 1p....Enc.wanting.... Sends paper on Petroleum in Pennsylvania
  - Letter to Prof. J.P. Lesley, July 6, 1878; 10-1/2x8; Ashburner, Charles A. (Charles Albert), 1854-1889
    Kane,[Pa.], A.L.S. 1p...Enc.wanting.... Sends additional pages of paper on petroleum in Pennsylvania.
  - Letter to J.P. Lesley, July 17, 1878; 8x5; Gurley, Wm. F. E. (William Frank Eugene Reed), b. 1854
    Danville, I11. A.L.S. 2p., end. Waiting for copies of his paper.
  - Letter to Prof. J.P. Lesley, July 18, 1878; 8x5; Gurley, Wm. F. E. (William Frank Eugene Reed), b. 1854
    Danville, Ill., A.L.S. 2p., end. Angry letter. Name wrong on his paper. Wants to see page proofs before publications. Mentions E.D.Cope.
  - Letter to Prof. J.P. Lesley, July 25, 1878; 8x5; Monks, Sarah P.
    Coldspring, N.Y., A.L.S. 1p., end.by M[ary] L[esley]. Thanks for copies of paper published by Society. Asks for drawings and manuscript.
  - Letter to E.B. Harden, Sept. 17, 1878; 10x8; Ashburner, Charles A. (Charles Albert), 1854-1889
    Kane, [Pa.], A.L.S. 1p. Corrections for his paper on petroleum in Pennsylvania. Encloses reprint of articles showing corrections(see in pamphlet collection).
  - Letter to Prof. J.P. Lesley:, Oct. 3, 1878; 10-1/2x8; White, I. C. (Israel Charles), 1848-1927
    Allegheny City, Pa., A.L.S. 1p., end. Sending manuscript on paleobotany. Discusses publication.
  - Letter to secretary of the American philosophical society [J.P.Lesley], Oct. 7, 1878; 8x5; Morton, Henry, 1836-1902
    Hoboken, N.J., A.L.S. 4p. Argument with S.Sadtler. Refers to C. Sellers.
  - Letter to Prof. J.P. Lesley, Oct. 9, 1878; 11x8-1/2; Fontaine, William Morris, 1835-1913
    Morgantown, W.Va., A.L.S. 2p., end. Seeks recommendation. Summarizes geological findings in Virginia.
  - Letter to Prof. J.P. Lesley, Oct. 10, 1878; 9-1/2x6; White, I. C. (Israel Charles), 1848-1927
    Morgantown, W.Va., A.L.S. 1p., end. Sending list of species for paper on paleobotany. Mentions W.Fontaine.
  - Letter to Prof. J.P. Lesley, Oct. 16, 1878; 11x8-1/2; Fontaine, William Morris, 1835-1913
    Morgantown, W.Va., A.L.S. 2p. Discusses his work on the geology of Virginia. Mentions W.Kerr. WB.Rogers(?), and R.Taylor, among others.
  - Letter to J. P[eter] Lesley, Nov. 20, 1878; 7x5; Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia
    [Phila.] L.S. 1p. Please permit Poinsett collection to be removed by agent of the Academy. Signature indecipherable.
  - Letter to J. P[eter] Lesley, Nov. 30, 1878; 10x8; Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia
    Phila., L.S.: W[illia]m S[amuel] W[aithman] Ruschenberger 1p., end.: Receipt for Poinsett collection to be returned on demand Asks him to deliver Poinsett collection to the Curator, Charles F. Parker, in accordance with A.P.S. resolution of Nov. 16, 1877. Cf. Proceedings, v.17, pp.273-4.
  - Resolution of thanks for deposit of A.P.S. numismatic collection, Dec. 5, 1878; 12-1/2x8; Numismatic and Antiquarian Society of Philadelphia
    [Phila.] A.D.S.: J. Hays Carson 1p. Motion made by C.H. Hart, seconded by Henry Phillips.
  - Letter to J. P[eter] Lesley, Dec. 6, 1878; 10x8; Numismatic and Antiquarian Society of Philadelphia
    Phila., A.L.S.: Henry Phillips 1p. Enc. Forwards copy of Society's resolution accepting deposit of A.P.S. numismatic collection. For enclosure, see Numismatic and antiquarian society. Resolution...Dec. 5, 1878.